Bored with your life?
对自己的生活感到厌倦了吗？
Dreaming of something different?
梦想着一些不一样的事情？
When I feel like that I look up and wonder what life would be like 400km above my head.
当我有那种感觉时，我会抬头仰望，想象在我头顶上方400公里处的生活会是什么样子。
That's where the International Space Station orbits the Earth, with six astronauts living and working on board, for months at a time.
那就是国际空间站环绕地球运行的地方，有六名宇航员在空间站上面生活和工作，每次一待就是好几个月。
How do they sleep?
他们怎么睡觉呢？
They spend the night floating in a sleeping bag inside a small cubicle on the ceiling.
他们晚上在天花板上的一个小隔间里，躺在睡袋中飘浮着睡觉。
American astronaut Sunita Williams explains: "It's like a little phone booth but it's pretty comfy and it doesn't matter if I turn over and sleep upside down.
美国宇航员苏妮塔・威廉姆斯解释说：“它就像一个小小的电话亭，但相当舒适，而且我翻个身倒立着睡觉也没关系。
I don't have any sensation in my head that tells me I'm upside down."
我的脑袋里没有任何感觉会告诉我自己是倒立着的。”
Brushing your teeth in a place where you can't have a tap or a sink can be a challenge.
在一个没有水龙头和水槽的地方刷牙可能是一项挑战。
Can you imagine the mess that running water would make in zero gravity?
你能想象在零重力环境下流动的水会造成怎样的混乱吗？
Canadian astronaut Chris Hadfield uses a straw to put a big blob of water from a sealed bag onto an ordinary toothbrush and adds a little toothpaste - which he has to swallow when he's done.
加拿大宇航员克里斯・哈德菲尔德用一根吸管从一个密封袋中吸一大滴水，滴在一把普通牙刷上，然后挤上一点牙膏——刷完牙后他还得把牙膏吞咽下去。
Daily exercise is essential.
日常锻炼是必不可少的。
The lack of gravity makes bones more brittle and muscles lose strength – so astronauts are encouraged to work out for at least two hours a day.
缺乏重力会使骨骼变得更加脆弱，肌肉也会失去力量——所以宇航员们被鼓励每天至少锻炼两个小时。
The role of astronauts in the International Space Station is to act as lab technicians for scientists back on Earth.
国际空间站中宇航员的角色是充当地球上科学家们的实验室技术员。
So they spend their time maintaining their environment and performing and monitoring experiments in a confined space about the size of a Boeing 747.
所以他们把时间花在维护他们的生活环境，以及在一个大约波音747飞机大小的密闭空间里进行和监测实验上。
Almost every task is carefully planned by mission control - although most astronauts spend their first days losing stuff until they get used to sticking everything they use to the walls with Velcro, duct tape or clips.
几乎每一项任务都由指挥中心精心规划——不过大多数宇航员在最初的几天里总是丢东西，直到他们习惯了用魔术贴、胶带或夹子把他们使用的所有东西都固定在墙上。
One of their most valued perks is the view from "the office", dominated by that gigantic blue ball down there, sitting in the darkness of space.
他们最珍视的福利之一是从“办公室”看到的景色，在黑暗的太空中，映入眼帘的主要是下方那个巨大的蓝色星球。
Wow!
哇！
Absolutely breathtaking!
真是令人叹为观止！